<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Yiming Cao</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/</link><description>Recent content on Yiming Cao</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.yiming-cao.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m Yiming Cao, a dedicated researcher with a rich background in architecture and a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Engineering from Southeast University. My academic journey has been deeply influenced by a fascination with historical urban landscapes and the application of modern analytical techniques to understand and preserve them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.yiming-cao.com/images/pic4.jpg" alt="about">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="research-focus">Research Focus&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Throughout my career, I&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate to engage in diverse research projects that span from the digital reconstruction of the Ming Dynasty&amp;rsquo;s Nanjing to analyzing the urban dynamics of Bhaktapur through GIS mapping. My work primarily focuses on blending historical insights with contemporary urban planning methodologies to offer new perspectives on sustainable development and heritage conservation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ancient Construction</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/ancient/ancient-construction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/ancient/ancient-construction/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="ancient-chinese-timberwork-design-northern-song-building-construction-in-yixing-suburbs">Ancient Chinese Timberwork Design: Northern Song Building Construction in Yixing Suburbs&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Tutor: Shi Hu, Tingli Jia Bachelor Studio Work, 2017, Southeast University&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This project delved into the architectural nuances of ancient Chinese timberwork, focusing on the construction techniques used during the Northern Song Dynasty. The study commenced with a detailed site analysis, incorporating traditional elements such as painting scrolls and poetic routes to define building placements that harmonize with the landscape and terrain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Digital Humanities</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/venice/venice-biennale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/venice/venice-biennale/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="venice-biennale---the-imperial-palace-courtyard-studies">Venice Biennale - the Imperial Palace courtyard studies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Venice International Architecture Biennale
-Chinese Pavilion, 2020 (Postponed to 2021, Jingdezhen due to COVID)&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="yuan-er-a-journey-through-courtyards">Yuan-er: A Journey Through Courtyards&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Project Synopsis: Featured at the 17th Venice International Architecture Biennale, the exhibition &amp;ldquo;Yuan-er—From the Mega to the Micro&amp;rdquo; delves into the evolution of the traditional Chinese courtyard. Through a detailed exploration of these spaces, the project connects historical architectural forms with their modern interpretations, revealing the continuity and transformation of communal living across ages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heritage Assessment</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/heritage/heritage-assessment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/heritage/heritage-assessment/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="heritage-assessment-urban-analysis-and-cultural-ecosystem-services-in-heritage-city-bhaktapur">Heritage Assessment: Urban Analysis and Cultural Ecosystem Services in Heritage City Bhaktapur&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Tutor: Mingze Chen, Submission to CELA, 2024&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study integrates the examination of spiritual places with the assessment of Cultural Ecosystem Services (CES) in Bhaktapur, a UNESCO World Heritage Site renowned for its intricate blend of tangible and intangible heritage. By merging field surveys, machine learning analysis of User Generated Content (UGC), and heritage walks, the research highlights how CES enhances human well-being through cultural recognition, travel enjoyment, and aesthetic experiences within the urban fabric of Bhaktapur.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Protection Planning</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/protection/protection-planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/protection/protection-planning/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="nanjing-ming-dynasty-city-wall-a-multidisciplinary-approach-to-urban-heritage-conservation">Nanjing Ming Dynasty City Wall: A Multidisciplinary Approach to Urban Heritage Conservation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Tutor:Peng Tang, Yuan Zhu, Nanjing &amp;amp; Roma &amp;amp; Firenze, 2018&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Protection Planning project for the Nanjing Ming Dynasty City Wall, a collaborative effort with Southeast University, Tianjin University, Rome University, and Florence University, aimed to integrate comprehensive protection strategies with urban renewal. This project focused on preserving the historical integrity of the city wall while enhancing the surrounding urban fabric to meet contemporary needs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Urban Analysis</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/analysis/urban-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/analysis/urban-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="urban-analysis-urban-dynamics-and-the-treasure-shipyards-influence-on-ming-nanjing">Urban Analysis: Urban Dynamics and the Treasure Shipyard&amp;rsquo;s Influence on Ming Nanjing&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Tutor: Wei Chen, Chapter of Master&amp;rsquo;s dissertation, 2022, Southeast University&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study delves into the transformative impact of the Nanjing Treasure Shipyard on Ming Dynasty Nanjing, examining how this pivotal industrial hub catalyzed significant urban and architectural developments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.yiming-cao.com/images/pic17.jpg" alt="about">&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="urban-planning-and-development">Urban Planning and Development&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>The construction of treasure ships and the subsequent expansion of the Treasure Shipyard were monumental feats of engineering that significantly influenced urban development strategies. This analysis explores how the shipyard’s expansion not only supported maritime endeavors but also stimulated surrounding industrial activities and facilitated the construction of key religious and civic structures. The integration of these elements into Nanjing&amp;rsquo;s urban fabric exemplifies the shipyard&amp;rsquo;s role in molding the city’s spatial and functional arrangements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Urban Design</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/design/urban-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/design/urban-design/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="readtory-renovation-planning-integrating-urban-design-and-heritage-conservation">Readtory Renovation Planning: Integrating Urban Design and Heritage Conservation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Guangzhou Urban Construction Development Co. Ltd, 2022&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Readtory renovation project represents a pivotal initiative in urban regeneration, focusing on the revitalization of a historic site into a vibrant cultural and community hub. As a key member of the project management team, my role spanned across various critical phases of the project, from initial field research and conceptual design to historical building assessment and the strategic selection of collaboration studios.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Works</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/works/vivamus-lacus-mauris/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/works/vivamus-lacus-mauris/</guid><description>&lt;p>Academic endeavors have consistently bridged historical insights with contemporary urban planning through advanced technological applications, beginning at Southeast University and extending through significant projects at institutions like the Meta Reliability Lab in London and the Nature AI Lab. These projects employ cutting-edge tools to tackle urban challenges effectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.yiming-cao.com/images/pic12.jpg" alt="about">
At the Meta Reliability Lab, the Urban Mobility and Analytics Workshop utilized technologies such as point cloud and object detection to analyze and enhance urban mobility solutions. This integration of geotagged data advanced the understanding of urban environments, aiding in the development of efficient city planning strategies.Similarly, the Computer Vision and Built Environment Extraction Workshop at Nature AI Lab harnessed social media image data to provide spatial insights into activity distribution across urban spaces, assisting planners in enhancing urban vitality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Digital Humanities</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/research-areas/service4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/research-areas/service4/</guid><description>&lt;p>Focus on translating and contextualizing ancient Chinese architectural terms using digital tools to enhance understanding across cultures and disciplines.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>historical urban analytics</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/research-areas/service1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/research-areas/service1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Utilizes big data and GIS to reconstruct ancient urban landscapes, providing insights into the evolution of urban planning and influencing modern methodologies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Urban Heritage &amp; Technology</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/research-areas/service3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/research-areas/service3/</guid><description>&lt;p>Integrates advanced GIS and digital mapping technologies to preserve and interpret the urban morphology of historical sites, enhancing regional preservation policies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ancient Building Methods</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/research-areas/service2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/research-areas/service2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Investigating the technical aspects of historical buildings where modern engineering methods provide new insights into ancient construction techniques.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/subheader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/subheader/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.yiming-cao.com/about">Exploring&lt;/a> the heart and soul of cities through the lens of history and the promise of modern analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Download portfolio</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/downloads/download2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/downloads/download2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Download portfolio&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>