<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homes on Yiming Cao</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/</link><description>Recent content in Homes on Yiming Cao</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ancient Construction</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/ancient/ancient-construction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/ancient/ancient-construction/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="ancient-chinese-timberwork-design-northern-song-building-construction-in-yixing-suburbs">Ancient Chinese Timberwork Design: Northern Song Building Construction in Yixing Suburbs&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Tutor: Shi Hu, Tingli Jia Bachelor Studio Work, 2017, Southeast University&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This project delved into the architectural nuances of ancient Chinese timberwork, focusing on the construction techniques used during the Northern Song Dynasty. The study commenced with a detailed site analysis, incorporating traditional elements such as painting scrolls and poetic routes to define building placements that harmonize with the landscape and terrain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Digital Humanities</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/venice/venice-biennale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/venice/venice-biennale/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="venice-biennale---the-imperial-palace-courtyard-studies">Venice Biennale - the Imperial Palace courtyard studies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Venice International Architecture Biennale
-Chinese Pavilion, 2020 (Postponed to 2021, Jingdezhen due to COVID)&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="yuan-er-a-journey-through-courtyards">Yuan-er: A Journey Through Courtyards&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Project Synopsis: Featured at the 17th Venice International Architecture Biennale, the exhibition &amp;ldquo;Yuan-er—From the Mega to the Micro&amp;rdquo; delves into the evolution of the traditional Chinese courtyard. Through a detailed exploration of these spaces, the project connects historical architectural forms with their modern interpretations, revealing the continuity and transformation of communal living across ages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heritage Assessment</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/heritage/heritage-assessment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/heritage/heritage-assessment/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="heritage-assessment-urban-analysis-and-cultural-ecosystem-services-in-heritage-city-bhaktapur">Heritage Assessment: Urban Analysis and Cultural Ecosystem Services in Heritage City Bhaktapur&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Tutor: Mingze Chen, Submission to CELA, 2024&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study integrates the examination of spiritual places with the assessment of Cultural Ecosystem Services (CES) in Bhaktapur, a UNESCO World Heritage Site renowned for its intricate blend of tangible and intangible heritage. By merging field surveys, machine learning analysis of User Generated Content (UGC), and heritage walks, the research highlights how CES enhances human well-being through cultural recognition, travel enjoyment, and aesthetic experiences within the urban fabric of Bhaktapur.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Protection Planning</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/protection/protection-planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/protection/protection-planning/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="nanjing-ming-dynasty-city-wall-a-multidisciplinary-approach-to-urban-heritage-conservation">Nanjing Ming Dynasty City Wall: A Multidisciplinary Approach to Urban Heritage Conservation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Tutor:Peng Tang, Yuan Zhu, Nanjing &amp;amp; Roma &amp;amp; Firenze, 2018&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Protection Planning project for the Nanjing Ming Dynasty City Wall, a collaborative effort with Southeast University, Tianjin University, Rome University, and Florence University, aimed to integrate comprehensive protection strategies with urban renewal. This project focused on preserving the historical integrity of the city wall while enhancing the surrounding urban fabric to meet contemporary needs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Urban Analysis</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/analysis/urban-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/analysis/urban-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="urban-analysis-urban-dynamics-and-the-treasure-shipyards-influence-on-ming-nanjing">Urban Analysis: Urban Dynamics and the Treasure Shipyard&amp;rsquo;s Influence on Ming Nanjing&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Tutor: Wei Chen, Chapter of Master&amp;rsquo;s dissertation, 2022, Southeast University&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study delves into the transformative impact of the Nanjing Treasure Shipyard on Ming Dynasty Nanjing, examining how this pivotal industrial hub catalyzed significant urban and architectural developments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.yiming-cao.com/images/pic17.jpg" alt="about">&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="urban-planning-and-development">Urban Planning and Development&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>The construction of treasure ships and the subsequent expansion of the Treasure Shipyard were monumental feats of engineering that significantly influenced urban development strategies. This analysis explores how the shipyard’s expansion not only supported maritime endeavors but also stimulated surrounding industrial activities and facilitated the construction of key religious and civic structures. The integration of these elements into Nanjing&amp;rsquo;s urban fabric exemplifies the shipyard&amp;rsquo;s role in molding the city’s spatial and functional arrangements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Urban Design</title><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/design/urban-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/design/urban-design/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="readtory-renovation-planning-integrating-urban-design-and-heritage-conservation">Readtory Renovation Planning: Integrating Urban Design and Heritage Conservation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Guangzhou Urban Construction Development Co. Ltd, 2022&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Readtory renovation project represents a pivotal initiative in urban regeneration, focusing on the revitalization of a historic site into a vibrant cultural and community hub. As a key member of the project management team, my role spanned across various critical phases of the project, from initial field research and conceptual design to historical building assessment and the strategic selection of collaboration studios.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/subheader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.yiming-cao.com/home/subheader/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.yiming-cao.com/about">Exploring&lt;/a> the heart and soul of cities through the lens of history and the promise of modern analysis.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>